A Guide to the Records of the Virginia Secretary of Administration, 2018-2021
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Records of the Virginia Secretary of Administration, 2018-2021
The Library of Virginia
53494
XX cubic feet (XX boxes)
Virginia. Office of Administration
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Privacy protected and confidential information is restricted from public access for 75 years per Code of Virginia 42.1-78. Privacy-protected information has been flagged and/or sealed, but not removed from the collection. Restricted information may include, but is not limited to: attorney-client privileged documents, medical information, and social security numbers.
Acquisition Information
Accession 53494 was transferred by the Office of the Secretary of Public Safety, 7 January 2022.
Historical Information
In 1970, the Governor's Management Commission Study recommended the creation of six "Deputy Governors" to assist the Chief Executive in his managerial duties. Compatible functions of government were grouped under these administrative heads, who would serve as the Governor's top management team.
XX
XX
XX
Scope and Content
The Secretary of Administration records consists of XX archival boxes and are divided into X series. Series have been designated for Correspondence and subject files; Correspondence and subject files - Assigned State Agencies, Governor Decision Requests; and Environmental Impact Statements. These records document the activities of the Office of the Secretary of Administration, as well as the agencies and boards which fall under its heading, during the gubernatorial term Gov. Ralph Northam (2018-2022).
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into the following series:
Series I. Correspondence and Subject Files - Assigned State Agencies
Series II. Correspondence and Subject Files - Secretary, 2018-2021
Series III. Governor Decision Requests, 2018-2021
Series IV. Environmenat Impact Statements, 2018-2021
Contents List
- Series I. Correspondence and Subject Files - Assigned State Agencies, 2018-2021., Extent: XX cu. ft. (XX boxes) (Box 1-XX)
  Correspondence and Subject Files - Assigned State Agencies, 2018-201721, is housed in XX archival boxes and is arranged alphabetically by agency. This series contains topical files and correspondence with the following agencies and boards that operated under the Secretary of Public Safety and Homeland Security:
  The correspondence and subject files contain correspondence between the agencies and the Office of the Secretary of Administration regarding issues that affect that particular agency or board. References to budgetary matters, litigation, studies and reports, board appointments, and legislation are frequently found in this material. These files may also provide supporting documentation and background information on many topics and include agendas, briefings, minutes, plans, presentations, proposals, publications, reports, and studies.
  Some topics include agency accomplishments, budget issues, correctional facilities, healthcare and mental health services, hurricane planning and preparedness (VDEM), initial briefings, legislative initiatives and presentations, parole, restrictive housing, school and campus safety, and unmanned aircraft systems, as well as records related to the Advisory Committee on Virginia ABC Information Technology Systems (ABC), Law Enforcement Expert Panel Review (ABC), Board of Corrections (DOC), Evidence Based Decision Making Initiative (DCJS), and Governor's Commission on Parole Review (VPB).
  - Chief Data Officer
    - Correspondence, 2018. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Compensation Board
    - Correspondence, 2018-2019. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Elections, Dept. of
    - Correspondence, 2018. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - General Services, Dept. of
    - Correspondence, 2018. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, 2019-2021. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Atlantic Coast Pipeline, undated. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Camp Pendleton, 2018. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Capital Outlay, 2018. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Capitol Master Plan Executive Committee, 2018 June 18. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Cheatham Annex, undated. (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Decision briefs, 2018. (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Decision memoranda, 2019. (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Decision memoranda, 2020. (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Decision memoranda, 2021. (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Emergency Declaration - Procurement, 2018. (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Hiring requests, 2018-2020. (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Innovations in State Government, 2019. (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Isle of Wight/Dept. of Juvenile Justice Project, 2018. (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - lactation rooms, 2018. (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Lee Monument, 2018. (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Legislation, 2018. (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Legislation, 2019. (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - On the Square Committee, 2018 July 24. (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Surplus Real Property, 2018-2021. (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Virginia Employment Commission Headquarters, 2019. (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Virginia State Capitol - 2019 Master Plan (Draft), 2019 Aug 5. (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Virginia War Memorial, 2018. (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Virginia Women's Monument, 2018-2019. (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Human Resource Management, Dept. of
    - Correspondence, 2018. (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence, 2019. (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Employee Experience (Magazine for Employees by Employees) (Draft), 2021 Nov. (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Policy Decision Brief - State Employee Health Plan, 2018 Mar. (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Virginia Information Technologies Agency
    - Correspondence, 2018. (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Final Recommendation Report - Comprehensive Infrastructure Agreement, 2015 Nov. (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Disentanglement Transition Plan, 2017-2018. (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Northrop Grumman Summaries, 2017 Dec. (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Sourcing Financial Update, 2018 Feb 2. (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Managed Security Services Contract Overview, 2018 Feb 2. (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - VITA's Line of Credit, 2018 Feb 2. (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Enterprise Ready Overview, 2018 Feb 8. (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Transition briefing, 2018 Feb 19. (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Bi-Monthly Update, 2018 Mar. (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Procedures Manual Breach - Position Summary, 2018 Mar 6. (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - IBM Mainframe Fees Proration - Position Summary, 2018. (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - CESC Internet Circuit Upgrade - Position Summary, 2018 Mar 8. (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - VSP Switches and Remediation - Position Summary, 2018. (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Messaging Options and Costs, 2018 Mar 12. (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - IT ISP Asset Ownership, 2018 May 4. (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Transition Assist Program, 2018 May 9. (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Quarterly Commonwealth Technology Portfolio (CTP) Update, 2018 Apr. (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Identity Management Standards Advisory Council (IMSAC), 2018 Apr 12. (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - IT Governance - Managing Technology Investments to Provide Value to the Citizens of Virginia, 2018 Apr 26. (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Transition Assist Program (SAIC), 2018 June 26. (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Transition Assist Program (SAIC), 2018 Aug 2. (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Messaging Service Remediation Plan, 2018 Sept 27. (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Platform Governance Maturity Plan, 2018 Oct. (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Financial Update, 2018 Oct 1. (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - VITA Election Day Readiness Plan, 2018 Oct 15. (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - MSI Governance and 12/15 Readiness Review, 2018 Oct 31. (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - VITA Management Readiness, 2018 Nov 7. (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - 12/15 Readiness Status, 2018 Nov 8. (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - VITA Transformation Update for the Secretary of Administration and Chief of Staff, 2019 Mar 6. (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Update for Secretary of Administration, 2019 Mar 12. (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Comprehensive Infrastructure Service Agreement briefing, undated. (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Series II. Correspondence and Subject Files - Office of the Secretary, 2018-2021., Extent: XX cubic feet (XX boxes). (Box X-X)
  Correspondence and subject files - Office of the Secretary, 2018-2021, is housed in XX boxes and is arranged alphabetically. Contains incoming correspondence, some outgoing correspondence, invitations and topical files of Secretary Moran. Includes correspondence from local, state and federal government officials, officials from other states, business owners, commissions, authorities and associations, as well as constituent correspondence. Topics include agency head meetings, agency updates, domestic violence, emergency preparedness and coordination, federal agencies, guns, homeland security, immigration, interoperability, mental health, opioids, other state agencies, staff meetings. Files may include agendas, briefings, correspondence, financial statements, invitations, memoranda, presentations, publications, and reports.
  - Alleghany Highlands Drone Zone, 2018 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Budgeting, 2018 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Collective bargaining by public employees, 2020 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Cybersecurity, undated (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Decision Brief - eVa, 2015 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - General Assembly, 2018 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Parental Leave, 2018-2019 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Policies and procedures, 2018 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Savings and Efficiencies Stategies (FY 2021 and FY 2022), 2019 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Secretary of Technology, 2018 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Short and Long-term Goals, undated (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Support Services - Financial Statements, 2018 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Support Services - Financial Statements, 2019 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Support Services - Financial Statements, 2020 (Box 5, Folder 14)
- Series III. Governor Decision Requests, 2018-2021., Extent: X cubic feet (X boxes). (Box X-X)
  Governor Decsion Requests, 2018-2021, are housed in X archival boxes and are arranged chronologically. This series documents
  - Governor Decision Requests, 2018 Jan. (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Governor Decision Requests, 2018 Feb. (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Governor Decision Requests, 2018 Mar. (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Governor Decision Requests, 2018 Apr. (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Governor Decision Requests, 2018 May 1-4. (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Governor Decision Requests, 2018 May 8-15. (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Governor Decision Requests, 2018 June. (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Governor Decision Requests, 2018 July. (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Governor Decision Requests, 2018 Aug. (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Governor Decision Requests, 2018 Sept. (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Governor Decision Requests, 2018 Oct 10-29. (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Governor Decision Requests, 2018 Oct 30-31. (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Governor Decision Requests, 2018 Nov 1-8. (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Governor Decision Requests, 2018 Nov 9. (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Governor Decision Requests, 2018 Nov 15-29. (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Governor Decision Requests, 2018 Nov 26. (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Governor Decision Requests, 2018 Dec 3. (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Governor Decision Requests, 2018 Dec 5-17. (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Governor Decision Requests, 2018 Dec 13. (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Governor Decision Requests, 2018 Dec 19-28. (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Governor Decision Requests, 2018 Dec 26. (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Governor Decision Requests, 2019 Jan 7-13. (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Governor Decision Requests, 2019 15-30. (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Governor Decision Requests, 2019 Feb 1-12. (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Governor Decision Requests, 2019 Feb 14-27. (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Governor Decision Requests, 2019 Mar. (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Governor Decision Requests, 2019 Apr 2-19. (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Governor Decision Requests, 2019 Apr 22-25. (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Governor Decision Requests, 2019 May. (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Governor Decision Requests, 2019 June 5-18. (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Governor Decision Requests, 2019 June 19-27. (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Governor Decision Requests, 2019 July. (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Governor Decision Requests, 2019 Aug 1-9. (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Governor Decision Requests, 2019 Aug 13-16. (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Governor Decision Requests, 2019 Aug 20-29. (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Governor Decision Requests, 2019 Sept 3-11. (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Governor Decision Requests, 2019 Sept 12-18. (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Governor Decision Requests, 2019 Sept 19-30. (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Governor Decision Requests, 2019 Oct 1-8. (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Governor Decision Requests, 2019 Oct 9-16. (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Governor Decision Requests, 2019 Oct 24-29. (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Governor Decision Requests, 2019 Oct 31. (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Governor Decision Requests, 2019 Nov 5-19. (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Governor Decision Requests, 2019 Nov 14. (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Governor Decision Requests, 2019 Nov 21. (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Governor Decision Requests, 2019 Nov 22-26. (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Governor Decision Requests, 2019 Dec 5-13. (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Governor Decision Requests, 2019 Dec 16-30. (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Governor Decision Requests, 2020 Jan. (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Governor Decision Requests, 2020 Feb. (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Governor Decision Requests, 2020 Mar. (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Governor Decision Requests, 2020 Apr. (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Governor Decision Requests, 2020 May. (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Governor Decision Requests, 2020 July. (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Governor Decision Requests, 2020 Aug. (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Governor Decision Requests, 2020 Sept. (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Governor Decision Requests, 2020 Oct. (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Governor Decision Requests, 2020 Nov. (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Governor Decision Requests, 2020 Dec. (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Governor Decision Requests, 2021 Jan. (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Governor Decision Requests, 2021 Apr. (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Governor Decision Requests, 2021 May. (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Governor Decision Requests, 2021 June. (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Governor Decision Requests, 2021 July. (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Governor Decision Requests, 2021 Aug. (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Governor Decision Requests, 2021 Sept. (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Governor Decision Requests, 2021 Oct. (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Governor Decision Requests, 2021 Oct. (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Governor Decision Requests, 2021 Nov. (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Governor Decision Requests, 2021 Dec. (Box 12, Folder 10)
- Series IV. Environmental Impact Statements, 2018-2021., Extent: X cubic feet (X boxes). (Box X-X)
  Environmental Impact Reports, 2018-2021, are housed in X archival boxes and are arranged chronologically. This series documents
  - Environmental Impact Reports, 2018 Jan. (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Environmental Impact Reports, 2019 Jan. (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Environmental Impact Reports, 2019 Nov. (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Environmental Impact Reports, 2019 Dec. (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Environmental Impact Reports, 2020 Feb. (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Environmental Impact Reports, 2020 Mar-Apr. (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Environmental Impact Reports, 2020 May. (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Environmental Impact Reports, 2020 June. (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Environmental Impact Reports, 2020 July. (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Environmental Impact Reports, 2020 Aug. (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Environmental Impact Reports, 2020 Sept. (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Environmental Impact Reports, 2020 Oct. (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Environmental Impact Reports, 2020 Nov. (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Environmental Impact Reports, 2020 Dec. (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Environmental Impact Reports, 2021 Jan. (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Environmental Impact Reports, 2021 Feb-Mar. (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Environmental Impact Reports, 2021 Apr. (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Environmental Impact Reports, 2021 May-June. (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Environmental Impact Reports, 2021 July 6-12. (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Environmental Impact Reports, 2021 July 14-22. (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Environmental Impact Reports, 2021 Aug-Sept. (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Environmental Impact Reports, 2021 Oct. (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Environmental Impact Reports, 2021 Nov. (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Environmental Impact Reports, 2021 Dec. (Box 15, Folder 5)